# 前幾天那個小 那個母狗哦 母狗它又生啦 你看
Hi everyone! The pup...The mother dog, the mother, gave birth again a few days ago. Look!
# 生了好多隻
She has born a lot of puppies.
# 我去看一下
Let's go and have a look.
# 這是它的飯飯
This is their meal.
# 哇 東一條西一條
Wa! One is here and one is there.
# 你看 一地都是狗崽
Look! The puppies are everywhere.
# 我想摸這個白 我想摸這個棕的
I wanna touch this white, I wanna touch this brown one.
# 天氣熱 它們都是 睡的亂七八糟的
It's hot. So they're all sleeping everywhere, here and there.
# 你看 那麼多堆 這兩隻黑的是小黑的
They're so scattered. These two black ones are Blacky's puppies.
# 剩下都是那母狗生的
And the rest are all the mother's.
# 因為小黑不會帶崽 所以拿到這裡給它帶
Blacky doesn't take care of the puppies at all. So I bring them to her mom.
# 它們兩個星兩姊妹嗎
Are these two puppies sisters?
# 對呀
Yea!
# 哪個是 哪個是女的哪個是男的 這兩個黑的
Which one, which one is a girl and which one is a boy? I mean these two black ones.
# 這個你要問它哦 我又不知道哦
You really gotta ask them. I have no way to tell.
# 你看這個是不是 這種產色的
Have a look at this one. Isn't it, what kind of colour is it?
# 它 它眼睛都不張開的呀
Why, why don't they open their eyes?
# 沒那麼快 要到二十天左右才張開
Not so soon. It takes around twenty days before they can open their eyes.
# 你看 這個就是 灰的 是不是
Look! This is, this is grey, isn't it?
# 我想摸
I wanna touch it.
# 它們都吃的好飽哦 八條狗崽都吃的好飽
They've all eaten a lot. All eight puppies have eaten a lot.
# 這個好漂亮哦 它想爬走
This is really pretty. It wants to run away.
# 哇 這個也好漂亮
Wa! This is also very pretty!
# 為甚麼這些老是動啊
Why are they always moving?
# 不知道 它害怕
No ideas. Perhaps they're scared.
# 你看這小狗
Have a look at this puppy!
# 你看 咕嚕咕嚕咕嚕咕嚕
Look! Gulu gulu gulu gulu
# 好可愛 這個哦
It's really cute, this one, oh.
# 像這樣抱著它
You can hold it here.
# 這也好可愛
This is also very cute.
# 它眼這樣閉著的
So its eyes are just closed.
# 這也好可愛 嗯
And this one is cute as well.
Um!
# 打哈欠 想睡覺
It's yawning. It wants to sleep.
# 睡在我手上多舒服啊 是不是 你看
Sleeping on my hands is so comfortable. Isn't it? Look!
# 要不要給一個給你玩
Do you wanna play with one of them?
# 要不要
Do you?
# 嘿嘿 妹妹也不敢
Hehe
Little girl doesn't dare.
# 不要是不是
You don't want, do you?
# 你敢是不是
But you dare, don't you?
# 嗯
Um...
# 你看 好可愛 要不要親它
Look! It's so cute. You wanna kiss it?
# 嘿嘿嘿嘿
Hehe hehe
# 你想往哪裡跑
Where exactly do you want to go?
# 好啦好啦好啦好啦 走了走了 刘星辰
Alright, aright, alright, alright! Let's go, let's go! Liu Xingchen!
# 你別提人家尾巴
Don't grab its tail!
# 好啦 小
Alright! Kids,
# 全部都調皮搗蛋 是不是 老是動人家
they're all little monsters, aren't they? They're always disturbing the puppies.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 讓它們 睡在這裡 等下晚上母狗它會回來
Let them, sleep here. The mother is gonna come back, later in the evening.
# 餵奶的
She'll feed them.
# 我去搞點好吃的給那個母狗吃
Let me go and fetch some good food for the mother.
# 個個都很健康哦
They're all in very good health.